They know we're here.
We'll be surrounded soon.
The Imperial Command is ours.
Let's get out of here.
It's not my job to protect you.
So if you want to live, try to keep up.
THE ELUSIVE
SAMURAI
When I give the signal,
everyone goes in together.
Damn it.
And take this, too!
I can't see the thieves
in all this smoke and light.
-My eyes!
-Get past the smoke!
Give me that.
I can hear them.
They used the fire as a distraction,
and they're climbing the wall
on the opposite side.
What…
Damn it.
I'm nowhere near as good with the bow
as Sadamune.
-Let's go!
-Westward!
Where is Sadamune?
The thieves scaled the wall and fled!
Gather your pride as Ogasawara's
retainers and don't let them get away!
That's Genba's signal.
-Time to lure them away.
-Yes.
Over there. They escaped on horseback.
I heard the sound
of horses starting to run,
but there was no sound
of the brats' footsteps
going from the wall to the horse.
The horses probably belong to
their allies,
hidden beforehand as a lure.
And there was no sound
of anyone walking away.
If that's the case,
that means they're very close.
The brats must be in the forest,
holding their breaths.
Where
are
you?
It's Sadamune's suck-up,
Sukefusa Ichikawa.
The guy's got the ears of a fox.
It isn't fair he's hunting us down
on this dark of a night.
My illusions to fool his blind spot
won't help us.
This is bad. We'll be caught at this rate.
Should I sell this kid out at this point?
I messed up.
I thought it'd be fun to teach this naive,
spoiled brat
the harsh realities of the world.
This one…
I'm leaving behind.
If it's just me, I can make it.
-No!
-No one can hear my stealthy steps!
In hide-and-seek,
you'll absolutely be caught
if you move from such a close distance!
NANBOKUCHO GAME OF TAG
I found you.
ALL-HEARING DEMON
SUKEFUSA ICHIKAWA
Ugh. Damn it.
I shouldn't have brought this long sword.
It's impossible to maneuver.
Hey.
I'm okay.
The blade hit the tree. It's just a cut.
Why did you save me
when I was going to abandon you?
You could have run away by yourself.
I doubted you earlier.
I can't apologize to you if you're dead.
My mental fortitude is weak,
and I don't have what it takes.
In the future, I may doubt you again.
But I promise,
I will never betray you.
What…
I like escaping with you.
With you and your tricks,
I can escape from strong demons
I could never escape from on my own.
Thinking about it that way,
I can't help but get excited.
Even if you're ever cornered,
or if you ever betray me,
when we run away, we run together!
Tokiyuki has been betrayed
by countless people,
but he has never betrayed anyone.
At a time when betraying and deserting
one's allies was commonplace,
Tokiyuki could be said to be
a devoted general.
Where are those thieves? Damn it.
I can't see as well in the dark
at this age.
Silly…
I'm here for you.
Oh, it's you, Ichikawa!
He's speaking to me casually?
With you by my side,
we can kill all the thieves in the dark!
I'm older and of a higher rank than him.
Why is he speaking to me so casually?
I've hidden some horses
at the end of these woods.
We're almost there.
Okay, let's go.
The bleeding isn't stopping.
He can't keep moving for much longer.
What?
A thunderbolt?
He's back.
That's Sadamune's arrow.
Don't be stupid.
The sound of his horse
is about one meter away.
In this pitch darkness,
he shouldn't be able to aim so accurately!
We still have some time
until we reach our horses.
I can't outrun that arrow
with this kid with me.
This damn brat.
Trust my ears and fire, Sadamune.
I've entombed many in darkness
with these hands.
Now, Sadamune.
Shall we start off
by shooting down that wounded brat?
Yes, Ichikawa.
Show my arrow the way
with your perfect hearing.
If the obligation was invisible,
I could ignore it.
But an obligation I can see?
I have to repay it!
Are you two old geezers having fun?
What a pain. But I'll take on both of you.
Hmm? That fox mask.
I've heard of it before.
You're Genba Kazama, that thief's brat.
Kazama?
Yes. His father was disgraced
as a warrior for using unfair tactics,
and so he was exiled from his clan.
Then, he fell to thievery.
Kazama is a branch
of the Suwa clan in Shinano…
You've come under Yorishige's order
to steal the Imperial Command, huh?
Imperial Command?
What are you talking about?
I just thought
I'd make fun of you soldiers.
Birds? I can't tell
where the sounds are coming from!
I don't know about killing,
but morphing I know a thing or two about!
And I won't stand losing
to you boring soldiers.
No!
Oh. Oh, no.
You try to bewilder me
with your excessive movement!
You underestimate me!
You can't dodge me from this distance!
Sadamune.
-What?
Take this!
He cut my bowstring! That's unfair!
Unfair?
My accomplice loves these tricks.
You can't appreciate them
because you're old,
like the old and dusty documents
in that warehouse.
So I told my accomplice, too…
Paper isn't something to steal.
It's more fun to burn.
Oh?
The word "Shinobi" appears in one of
the oldest epics of Japan, the Taiheiki,
which records the events of this time.
"Bold and forthright" would begin to
disappear from the warrior's vocabulary.
Those who can infiltrate like spies with
subversive tactics began to be prized.
And thus, the ninja was born.
He disappeared?
In the split second we were shocked
by the warehouse on fire!
Sadamune. Could the Imperial Command
still be in there?
We'll catch the wounded and make him
confess who the ringleader is!
This sound of hooves.
It's the two decoys running away!
I can't catch up from this distance.
That fox-masked brat tricked us all!
I saw the signal to come,
and look how our lord
is in such bad shape!
Hey, Genba!
Be more careful with the Young Lord!
Yeah, that's right!
No, you guys. It's all thanks to Genba
we're able to outrun those two.
It was fun.
I hope we get to play hide-and-seek again.
My Genba.
If you find a lord you'd like to serve
even without turning a profit,
you should still take the money.
Even if you plan on serving
till the next life,
you should still take the money!
Fine. If I can have one province.
I won't let you off the hook
if you don't pay.
If you cannot pay,
I'll track down your children,
your grandchildren,
and all your relatives.
That means you'll play tag
with my children too?
That's not what I'm saying!
I'm saying
you better take back the country!
So you're saying you'll play with us
after we take back the country?
Why are you like this?
Come on, Genba. Stop moving!
We're gonna collide!
Go home!
We won't clear out
if you don't have an Imperial Command.
I bet you brutes are lying
about the Imperial Command
so you can steal our land.
That's right! I won't listen to someone
without an Imperial Command!
If you're mad about it,
show me the Command!
Damn those Suwa citizens.
Fighting back uselessly. But I can get
another Imperial Command in a month!
Your eviction notice is simply extended!
There's bad news, my lord!
We can't take the Suwa land anymore.
What?
KYOTO
I took down the Kamakura shogunate.
I took down about 1,000 important
retainers of the Kamakura shogunate.
I commanded Takauji's rebellion.
It was horrible.
I had to fly back to the past with Buddha
and go on a journey.
The majority are seeking reward, and
lying about their achievements to get it.
It'll take years to determine
who's lying and who's telling the truth!
We'll never get to discuss
our official duty.
-What a pain!
-Sir!
The Emperor said, "What a pain!"
MAINTAIN STATUS QUO
"Territories other than Hojo's
will remain as is.
Suwa's will also remain undisputed."
-This is infuriating!
-Let's be patient.
Our chance will come, you know.
You!
He is speaking to me casually?
Suwa!
We did it!
We're safe!
Buying time really paid off.
If we had simply handed our territory over
to Ogasawara,
we'd never get it back.
I must thank you for saving our land
and also for securing a new,
dependable retainer.
I feel better knowing Genba's
on our side now.
-Though his personality is vulgar.
-Pour me more, pour me more!
With his tricks,
I could see him sneaking
into Takauji's sleeping quarters
and slicing his head off just like that.
That's impossible.
Takauji cannot be assassinated.
Here is a good opportunity, Lord Tokiyuki.
As I've said before,
you should know your enemy.
Takauji Ashikaga is someone
not even I can estimate.
I see you've finally moved with a few men.
EMPEROR GODAIGO'S SON
PRINCE MORIYOSHI
But this shall be your grave.
Your Highness,
I reverently celebrate
your appointment as shogun.
Your Highness,
why do you have to keep coming
for my life?
You are sure to betray
the Emperor one day.
I will stain my hands
for the sake of my father!
Protect the lord!
The lower-ranked soldiers
don't stand a chance.
Armed peasant thieves, monks,
and even rogue states.
Those that follow him are indeed varied.
His charisma draws people in.
Lord, allow me.
No, the prince is after only me.
If I speak to him one-on-one, I'm sure
we'll dissolve any misunderstandings.
Is that okay, brother?
It's no problem.
It's merely the Imperial shogun
and rogues.
Your Highness!
-It's Takauji!
-Kill him!
Please,
settle down.
Don't be intimidated! Go!
Oops.
There are many of you.
Takauji Ashikaga.
My gut was right.
You're a monster who shouldn't be
allowed to walk the planes of this life.
Oh, wait just a moment, Your Highness.
We'll be alone soon enough.
Right. That's done.
Please trust me, Your Highness.
I am loyal and devoted to the Emperor.
I couldn't win
if it were just me against him.
But I'm not alone.
If we combine everyone's efforts together,
then one day…
What's all this commotion?
His Highness has unsheathed his sword.
You guys. You came just in time.
Hurry, we need reinforcements--
It's Lord Takauji.
It's Lord Takauji!
It's actually Lord Takauji!
Are you all right, my lord?
Are you hurt?
It's nothing too bad.
Oh, I'm glad.
Lord Takauji…
I'm worried. Let's examine you
in the government office.
My allies from yesterday…
Why are they over there?
My Emperor.
We cannot let that man in.
Something not human writhes within him.
Emperor!
Lord Takauji.
That happened in Kyo?
He has military might,
which makes it impossible
to assassinate him.
He's also got an otherworldly charm.
That's Takauji Ashikaga.
The person whose popularity
exceeds the Emperor's own son
is a different beast
from the Takauji Ashikaga you know.
Once again, Lord Tokiyuki,
are you prepared to face an opponent
who stands at the top of this world?
Young Lord!
Help me with Genba!
He's wasted
and touching shrine maidens' butts!
And to top it off,
he's jumping around the room…
-Swish, swish.
-People have drawn their swords
because he's jumping around saying
he's gonna sprinkle pee everywhere!
The story of the people at the top
just turned into a story
about the people at the bottom.
Shall we, my lord?
We have to discipline this rude fox.
Yes.
Mr. Yorishige.
You gave me allies.
You gave me a way to fight.
And you gave me self-confidence.
They may still be small,
but they're all treasures you gave me
that I'm proud of.
No matter how much stronger Takauji is,
I won't give up.
I'll collect more treasures
and try as many times as it takes!
Hey, Genba!
Takauji and Tokiyuki.
An invincible lion,
and a rabbit not even on his radar.
There! Get him!
-Oh! Yeah, yeah, that's it!
-Over there!
The lion doesn't know yet
that a day will come
where he will fear the small rabbit.
Fluff fluff, fluff fluff, fluff fluff,
fluff fluff.
Translated by Emily Walton
EPISODE 7 (YEAR OF 1333)
CHILDREN IN WINTER
Let's go!